<Document>
	# The Gas Turbine
	<Box>
		<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasTurbineNormal" Scale="1.5"/>
	</Box>

	The Gas Turbine is where the power actually gets made.

	It takes in hot gas from the [textlink="Nuclear Reactor" link="NuclearReactor"] and outputs electricity and sends colder gas back to the Reactor.

	The amount of energy made by the Turbine is affected by its RPM, which is adjusted through Flow Rate and Stator Load.

	### Flow Rate
	The Flow Rate determines how much gas goes through the Turbine every second.

	The higher the Flow Rate, the higher the RPM of the Turbine.

	Flow Rate is usually set to allow maximum flow through the Reactor core, which can be found by the following equation: 
    <Box>
        [color=#a4885c]100 * number of gas channels + 200[/color]
    </Box>

	### Stator Load
	The Stator Load determines how much power is made by each revolution of the Turbine.

	The higher the Stator Load, the lower the RPM of the Turbine.

	Stator Load is usually adjusted to ensure the Turbine stays at optimal RPM.

	### RPM
	The RPM (Rotations Per Minute) represents how fast the Turbine is spinning.

	The Turbine has an optimal RPM, where it will produce the most power.

	Going faster or slower than optimal will result in poor performance.

	## Turbine Status Indicators
	The Turbine has a set of status indicators to warn operators of dangerous conditions or faults.

	### Overspeed
	The Turbine RPM is too high.

	If the Turbine RPM gets too high, it will start to take damage.

	Prolonged time spent at overspeed or excessive overspeed will cause the Turbine to [color=red]tear itself apart[/color].

	Damage to the Turbine can be repaired with a [color=yellow]welder[/color], though it will likely take multiple attempts to fully repair it.

	### Overtemp
	The gas going into the Turbine is too hot.

	If the gas coming into the Turbine is hotter than 2726C (3000k), it will trigger an emergency purge valve and dump the gas into the room.

	This hot gas can cause serious burns to personnel or even a fire, if the gas is flammable.

	### Stalling
	The gas is not hot enough for the set stator load.

	Stalling is where the gas going into the Turbine isn't "pushing" hard enough to overcome the stator load's resistance.

	### Undertemp
	The gas going into the Turbine is too cold.

	If the gas is at or below room temperature (20C), there is no energy for the Turbine to take out of it.

	## Turbine Parts
	<Box>
		<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NuclearFabricator"/>
	</Box>
	<Box>
		<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SteelGasTurbineBlade" Caption="turbine blade"/>
		<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SteelGasTurbineStator" Caption="stator"/>
	</Box>

	Turbine parts are what define how well the turbine functions.

	Turbine parts are made in the Nuclear Fabricator from a set of [textlink="materials" link="NuclearMaterials"].

	The Turbine is capable of accepting two different types of parts: Blades and Stators

	### Turbine Blades
	Turbine blades govern the integrity and inertia of the turbine.

	Higher integrity means it can take more damage before failing, making it generally safer.

	Higher inertia means it will take more energy to change the RPM, which leads to smoother operation.
	
	### Stators
	Stators affect the power efficiency and output of the Turbine.
</Document>