<Document>
 # CGP ROE
 ## Overview
 
 -- The purpose of this document is to outline general procedures and rules of engagement for the CGP. The emphasis will be on peacekeeping above enforcement of laws. As the opinion of the author is that a strong non commissioned officer corp is the backbone of any force, this will be reflected in the procedures, and rules of engagement will be flexible to allow for leaders on the ground to make adjustments on the fly as needed. As such, this document is written aimed primarily at them, the non commissioned officer. Any others reading this document should view this through their lens, for a better understanding of their orders or how to better direct the NCO.
 
 Under regular conditions, peacekeeping is the primary focus, with enforcement of laws being a means to that end. Only under compelling need shall any right of any resident be abridged or denied, and only for the purposes of protecting those rights from those that would seek to deny them.
 
 All uses of force are to meet the level required for an encounter. While the initial path of engagement is ask, tell, make, not all encounters are so clean. As long as the intent of these orders is followed and you can articulate the reasoning, you are unlikely to have to explain yourself to a grand jury.
 
 Just about anything in this document may be loosened or even waived in interest of peaceful interactions and furtherance of cooperation in more significant interactions. A small possession charge waived or ignored can lead to more cooperation when you need it the most. Do not underestimate the willingness for local forces or civilians to throw themselves into the bloodiest messes to save a trusted peacekeeper. If you can earn that favor, you will have already won. For example if a resident’s only crime is possession of an otherwise restricted item, they may be permitted to keep it if promptly licensed. Voluntary compliance is always preferable to an arrest or confiscation.




 # Section 1, rules of engagement
  
 -- 1. Every engagement should begin with a level of force appropriate to the severity of the threat. Any situation where verbal commands suffice should be handled with such. Escalation may be necessary in some cases, but must be done with sufficient reason. Ask for compliance, order compliance, then enforce compliance. 

 -- 2. When responding to a known dangerous threat, a long arm may be presented if the situation warrants it. If possible this long arm should be accompanied by at least one officer armed with less than lethal. Where possible, this LTL should be the first to fire, ideally disabling the threat without serious bodily harm. All efforts to clear the area should be used to ensure civilians are not caught in the crossfire or used as hostages. Consider the composition of the opposing force when determining your own level of force and equipment used. If at all possible, the subject should be warned explicitly that they may be fired on if they do not comply immediately, regardless of whether you are using lethal force or LTLs.

 -- 3. When entering an active hostile engagement, or any situation which is highly likely to turn violent, elevated force may be used. In a case where the threat is active and civilians are confirmed to have vacated the area, overwhelming force may be used as the situation commander determines necessary, within reason. This may include suppressive fire, explosives, up to and including patrol ship grade artillery support.

 -- 4. If at any point during any engagement the opportunity to affect an arrest or capture of a hostile presents itself the effort should be made to capture the hostile combatant, and as soon as is safe and practical, their injuries stabilized. Local medical teams may be enlisted for this purpose if it can be done safely. This shall not be considered deputizing, and may be paid at a rate of 20,000 an hour, or per complete engagement, whichever is greater. Every effort must be made to keep this medic safe and away from danger. This is done specifically to allow the corpsman, if present, to focus on treating wounded closer to the fight, while the medic themselves works safely in the rear akin to a field hospital.

 -- 5. In the event of active threats, the priority shifts away from preserving life to ending the threat, as the surest way to stop the violence is to end the threat. While this is not a carte blanche license to kill indiscriminately, the main priority becomes ending the threat. This is by reason that the threat will continue to kill until they are stopped. Stopping to treat wounded in the middle of the fight takes you out of the fight as well as the incapacitated friendly, which allows the threat to remain active longer. Leave medical care to the corpsman and the trailers, your objective is end the threat. 


 -- 6. Uniforms should be worn according to the current situation at hand. On standard patrols with no active threat, patrol suits are sufficient. Combat suits should be worn when entering a situation expected to turn violent, but not during regular procedural patrols. Experimental suits by nature of being experimental are niche tools that should be used sparingly, and are not to be worn for standard day to day use.

 -- 7. Despite being so low on the list, this is one of the most important notes. A dead peacekeeper helps nobody and simply inflates the body count. Unfortunately due to the very nature of conflict, not everyone gets to go home… This does not mean you need to throw your life away meaninglessly. Use your best judgment, knowing your own capabilities. If a fight is not one you can win, or affect any meaningful change, there is no shame in withdrawing. 

 -- 8. When possible, investigation of a particular subject is understated in value. Investigating a subject prior to a raid can ensure you find the correct target, rather than a civilian in the wrong place at the wrong time. If you can catch a subject in the commission of a crime, all the better. A non violent criminal being caught in the commission of their crime is far less likely to fight. If you can present a pile of evidence for them on the spot, rather than simply one possession charge, you will find yourself with a much more substantial charge. In a short phrase, give them the rope and let them tie their own noose.

 -- 9. When any subject is captured and detained or arrested, every reasonable effort must be made to care for their wounds and maintain their health and relative comfort. If the subject has any health requirements (eg. Dietary restrictions, atmosphere preferences) all reasonable efforts to meet these needs must be made. The subject should not be mocked, demeaned, abused, or otherwise harmed where not strictly necessary. 


 # Section 2, administrative procedures 


 -- 1. Licensing. Any license may be revoked for sufficient criminal activity involving the licensed items. For example a C3 license may be revoked for unlawful carry or use in commission of a crime. That same license should not be revoked for petty crimes such as vandalism, but may be revoked if behavior indicates a likelihood of further misuse.

 --    1. C2 licenses are generally a shall issue license, only to be denied in cases where a long standing habit of misuse of this license. C2 licenses are generally applicable to weapons suitable for general self defense, hunting, and most purposes. These weapons are generally considered very directed and not hard to control their effects.
   
 --    2. C3 licenses are to be issued as appropriate, to known trusted parties who can articulate a purpose appropriate to the item. These items shall be engraved with a serial number and logged to its owner. Only one item may be licensed to any individual at any time. This item may be turned in, and then the owner may be allowed to receive another license for a different item. Any license shall also cover ancillary items required for proper operation, to include ammunition and magazines. C3 licensees should have a record of being trustworthy and generally well behaved, and should be able to articulate a specific purpose. C3 weapons are generally considered to be more destructive than average, harder to control the effects, or have few to no legitimate uses. Licenses for propelled explosives are generally not issued, as they are uniquely dangerous to not only the target, but also to the user, bystanders, and serve few civilian or even security purposes.
   
 --    3. Search warrants may be issued in cases where there is probable causetWe to believe a search would find contraband or evidence of a crime. A search warrant may be requested by any peacekeeper, but must be approved by the the master at arms or above. In absence of any other CGP command, two regular grade peacekeepers OR the current most senior may petition to any civilian level regional command to sign off on the warrant. A warrant must outline the search subject, the areas to be searched, the purpose for the search, and the explicit items being searched for. If the named items are found they may be taken for evidence. Other contraband without an associated license may be taken at discretion, but must not be charged for. If the named item is found it is to be used for evidence purposes and the possessor charged if appropriate.
   
 --    4. After commission of a proven crime items directly used in the crime or directly facilitating it may be seized. This can include arms, weapons, armor, or explicitly weaponized materials. This shall never include material silos or their contents, legal fabricators, lawfully possessed medicine, ship components, or tools necessary for lawful commerce or means to support one’s self.

 -- 5. Businesses, specifically vendors and merchants, are generally exempt from licensing for many items, as they are not the end user but merely selling it. A business may however be expected to license their operations. The merchant may be required to verify license validity for relevant items, and in some cases, keep records of what was told to who, and notify CGP of certain sales so they may ensure the buyer acquires the appropriate licensing. However, a merchant who willfully disregards these rules may have their entire contraband stock seized, by reason of being unable or unwilling to meet the obligations of the role.
   
 -- 6. The Master at Arms or commodore may opt to, instead of disposing of heavy or niche weapons as encountered, opt to log them into the outpost arms register and retain them in the armory for issuing for special purposes as deemed necessary. These weapons should be issued out only when a specific case has deemed them necessary, and not handed out arbitrarily. This should ideally not include stealth items or other “dirty trick devices.”


 # 2. Threats 
 
 --    1. External threats such as automated haulers, UIVs, or any other threat from without, may be eliminated by reason of invasive forces. Peacekeepers may opt to accompany civilians and mercenaries onto these UIVs. This may be done for example as a force multiplier for the boarding parties, medical recovery, encouraging better cohesion and familiarity with local residents, and controlling the flow of arms and other contraband into the sector. In these cases the peacekeeper may choose to act as a team leader for the boarding party. The peacekeeper may then purchase contraband off of the boarding party at the current rate set by central or the commodore if different. Bluespace threats may be boarded alone without CGP accompaniment with a valid bluespace permit.
   
 -- 2. Internal threats such as common criminals and pirates are still residents, and thus are to be afforded the same protections as anyone else. 
   
 -- 3. In the case of a dedicated foreign threat, that is an invading force, CGP shall prioritize delaying the attacking force to allow time for civilians to flee the area. Mercenaries may be employed in these dire times. This section is necessarily short as not to get bogged down in procedures, rather allowing flexibility in the field to meet changing circumstances. 
   
 -- 4. Officers may opt to place a bounty on wanted criminal. However, the bounty must be for at least 2.5x the cost for the theoretical fines and the crime and circumstances must be sufficient to risk the public who may attempt to capture the subject. 
   
 -- 5. Any potential bounty hunters must be informed that a good faith attempt to capture the subject alive, or otherwise enable medics to save them. There is no purpose in sentencing a closed casket… Consider a much lower payout for any subjects brought in dead or dying.
   
 -- 6. Occasionally a Concordian vault will break down and will make an emergency stop in our sector. This vault is to be guarded. Part of it is your payroll, so do not lose it.
 
 -- 7. Occasionally a Mil-Tech arms cache will be intercepted from FTL. You are not to allow it to be raided, as the contents are contraband. You are to guard this cache while remote teams hack the system so it can be FTL extracted to a secure location for site exploitation.


 # 3. Smugglers
 -- 1. Occasionally smugglers send a fax to a wrong number. If one of these faxes is received, be it directly or offered by a local resident, the locations discovered may be staked out or immediately closed off. While closing off that route stops that one route, there is always more. Consider staking out a drop instead to catch the smuggler’s mule in the commission of the crime.
   
 -- 2. When encountering a pod, do not take the crates from inside. Internal traps create undue risk to personnel, and the risk of interception is not worth it.
   
 -- 3. Some may be tempted to search any ships moving around cargo depots. However, they are still subject to protections against unreasonable search and seizure. Such ships may only be searched with a valid search warrant. These cargo depots service more than crime after all.
   
 -- 4. Calling a stash for purposes of sealing it and reporting it is strictly prohibited, as it treads too close to entrapment.


 # 4. Sentencing and crime
 -- 1. When sentencing for any crime ensure the crimes are proven beyond a reasonable doubt, and that any sentences match the crime. Sentences may be enhanced for particularly egregious crimes or repeat offenses.
   
 -- 2. When confining a prisoner, ensure that all dangerous items are removed from the prisoner and secured in their locker, or confiscated if required for evidentiary purposes or as a result of use in criminal activity.
   
 -- 3. Exercise caution to not oversentence. Not every crime is deserving of the maximum possible sentence, and not every cooperation or surrender deserves the reductions if the surrender is offered in bad faith or there is no remorse for the crime committed. 
   
 -- 4. Do not attempt to pull out implants without due cause. It is deemed a violation of bodily autonomy to check for an implant without a valid warrant or due cause, and places the one checking at undue risk.


 # 5. Roles of the department and its staff
 -- 1. Commodore: The head of the department, highest rank in the department. They answer directly to sector command and are responsible for the highest functions in the department. Responsibilities include delegation of training, interfacing directly with sector command, managing disputes between other senior positions, and being the primary interface with other command staff in the sector. 
   
 -- 2. Master at Arms: The ‘boss’ of the outpost itself. Though they are technically positioned below the commodore, they are to be the main keyholder for the outpost, it is their primary responsibility. Their tasks include maintaining the outpost, ensuring the armory is stocked, ensuring operations internally are managed properly, ensuring integrity of the brig, ensuring the prisoners are effectively and humanely contained, and ensuring the outpost is stocked with food, and directing the officers for furtherance of these goals.
   
 -- 3. IAA: Internal Affairs Agent, technically outside of the chain of command, operating alongside it. They act as the detective investigating crimes within and without the department, auditing department operations and paperwork, investigating complaints against the department or its officers, and work to improve relations of the department with the public. The IAA may, if confronted with evidence of a crime, investigate any member of the department for corruption or any crime and may, if sufficient evidence is found, strip any position of rank and petition to sector command for revocation of their law enforcement licenses and confine them to the brig.
   
 -- 4. Corpsman: Technically operating alongside the chain of command as well, the corpsman ‘floats’ between assignments as assigned, going to whatever operation they are needed in. The corpsman is responsible for medical care of the department, its prisoners, and others within its immediate care, and creating the medications needed for the task. The corpsman is generally not intended to act as a general medical responder. The corpsman is expected to remain at the rear of most engagements, only moving up when it is known to be safe.
   
 -- 5. Senior peacekeeper: The SRPk is the NCO, who this guide is written for. They are the supervisors for the regular and junior peacekeepers, taking commands from the commodore and the MAA, then parsing those commands down to the peacekeepers with understanding of the intent of the orders. They are the primary ones responsible for training new peacekeepers, continuing education for other peacekeepers, low level dispute resolution between other peacekeepers, and primarily the one in command of any local incident they are managing.
   
 -- 6. Peacekeeper: The most common of the ranks, but by no means any less important. Peacekeeper orders are generally fluid, but tend to follow the general orders. Peacekeeper’s roles include patrol, enforcement of law, dispute resolution for civilians, and “Any other duties as assigned.
   
 -- 7. Junior peacekeeper: Our cadets, our future peacekeepers in training. Their role is simple; to learn the job. They should follow their peacekeeper or whoever they are assigned to for training. If any items are required for their duties, they should be issued by their assigned trainer or the Master at Arms.

</Document>
